>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 多年来，有人叫嚣着 JavaScript，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: For years,
there was clamoring that JavaScript,
如果这些模块像设计图案那么重要
if the modules were so
important as a design pattern,
那么我们就应该为他们提供一流和语法的支持。
then we ought to have first class and
syntactic support for them.
所以我们最终加入了 ES6 模块。
And so we finally added ES6 modules.
ES6 模块， >> 凯尔 - 辛普森:
ES6 modules,
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Are,
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 好吧，让我说
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Well, let me just say
他们是正在进行中的工作
they're a work in progress.
应该是当 ES6 规格落地的时候我们就有模块和
It should have been that when the ES6
spec landed, we just had modules and
那么在几个月或一年的时间里，它就在所有环境中。
then within a few months or a year,
it was just in all environments.
不幸的是我们有些程序崩溃了
Unfortunately, we had somewhat
of a process breakdown,
就像我能那样大方的说 TC39 没有真正的
to be as generous as I can,
in that TC39 didn't really
与 Node.js 对话有关模块语法的计划。
talk to Node.js about their plans for
the module syntax.
Node.js 没有真正地与 TC39 有关
And Node.js didn't really talk
to TC39 about the fact that what
它们的规范与 Node.js 不兼容。
they were about to spec was
incompatible with Node.js.
所以这个规格落地了，然后一年半之后，终于有人
And so that spec landed, and then a year
and a half later, somebody finally
意识到这两个人应该开始谈论这个不相容的问题。
realized that the two of them should
start talking about that incompatibility.
在过去两年半的时间里我们讨论过
And for the last two and a half years,
we've had this cluster f of discussions
我们要在这个生存危机中做些什么
and, what are we gonna do in this
existential crisis of we have this thing
它在规范中工作在浏览器中但是单一最大的代码
that's in the spec and it works in
browsers, but the single largest code
存储库是否是 NPM 完全不兼容的 ?
repository ever invented, aka NPM,
it's completely incompatible?
那我们该怎么办
So what are we gonna do?
好消息是他们一直在努力
Good news is they have been working on it,
一些很聪明的人一直在努力
some really smart people
have been working on it.
坏消息是只有坏的妥协
The bad news is there's
only bad compromises
当你把这条路弄下去的时候
when you get that far down the road.
其中一个，我认为是非常可怕的妥协，
And one of those, what I consider
to be really terrible compromises,
即在节点中可互换使用 ES6 模块，
is that to use ES6 modules
interchangeably in Node,
你得用另一个文件扩展名来代替 js
you're gonna have to use a different
file extension, mjs instead of js.
所以在节点内部有一个工作小组正在努力
So there's a working group within
Node that is working on getting full
需要有各种鱼子酱的模块支撑，
module support with whatever
caveats are necessary,
完整的模块支持节点，并且将在各个阶段执行。
full module support into Node, and
they're gonna do it over phases.
我想他们应该在这个时候
And they are expected,
I think, at this moment,
预计在 2020 年第一季度，陆地将会有稳定的陆地
they're expected sometime in Q1
of 2020 to land stable in Node
节点中模块支持的三或四个阶段的第一阶段。
the first phase of three or
four phases of module support in Node.
这就像是在规格出来的 5 年之后
That's like five years
after the spec came out.
所以这不太好，我们要等这么久。
So that's not great that we're
having to wait this long.
其实我是这个功能的粉丝，想写，但是
I actually am a big fan of this feature
and would like to be writing it, but
我一直站在一边，由于流量的原因，没有采用这种语法。
I have stayed on the sidelines and not
adopted this syntax because of the flux.
有一点他们确实说他们可能得把 TC39 改变
At one point they were literally saying
they may have to get TC39 to change
语法。
the syntax.
当我听到我说的时候我就在外面
And when I heard that I was like, I'm out.
我在等这件事安定下来好吗
I'm waiting for
this whole thing to settle down, okay?
所以有些人是早期的领养者，他们喜欢模块语法，
So some people were early adopters,
and they loved the module syntax, and
他们整天都在写它有错位的人什么的
they're writing it all day, and
they're having transpilers and whatever.
那就好
And that's fine.
如果您使用该语法，那么这很棒。
If you use that syntax, that's great.
我要给你简要介绍下它是什么
I'm gonna show you briefly what it is, but
我正和你分享我的观点
I'm just sharing with
you from my perspective,
我还没用这个语法直到整个节点都结束了对吗
I don't use this syntax quite yet until
this whole Node thing settles down, yes?
>> 演讲者 2: 是否有一个或两个句子关于
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Is there a one or
two sentence TLDR about what
不兼容性是在指定的规范之间写入的吗 ?
the incompatibility is
between the spec as written?
是和还是 ?
Does it have to do with or?
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 是的，这不是完全的问题，但是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Yeah, so
this is not the complete problem, but
这可能是一个更大的问题。
this is probably one of
the bigger problems.
节点希望保留您执行旧操作的能力
Node wants to preserve the ability for
you to do an old
样式需要新样式的 ES6 模块，或者
style require of a new style ES6 module,
or
执行旧样式公共 JS 模块的 ES6 模块样式导入。
do an ES6 module style import of
an old style Common JS module.
做一个或另一个也没那么糟
And it's not that bad to do one or
the other, but
你有一个循环就太疯狂了
it's really crazy when you have a cycle.
如果需要另一个，然后再导入另一个，并且
Where one has required the other,
and then imported the other, and
那些角落里的东西都是完全疯狂的
things just go completely
nuts in those corner cases.
因为他们拥有如此庞大而充满活力的生态系统
And because they have such a large and
vibrant ecosystem,
他们都得担心那些角落的案子
they have to worry about
all those corner cases.
所以有很多问题，他们一直在把它们筛选出来，做出妥协。
So there's a bunch of problems, they've
been sifting them out, making compromises.
我不喜欢结果
I don't like the outcome,
但我很高兴我们至少能在取得进展的过程中取得进展
but I'm glad that we're at least making
progress towards getting something.
这不会太棒但至少是件事好吗
It's not gonna be amazing, but
at least it's something, okay?
当它降落时，我完全打算改用语法。
And when it lands, I fully intend
to switch over to the syntax.
但现在，这就是如果我真的需要支持的事情之一，
But for now, this is one of those things
that if I really needed to support it,
我希望使用工具来编写语法，以便工具可以更改和
I would prefer a tool to write me
the syntax so that a tool can change and
解决这些问题。
deal with those problems.
这不是我的编写格式。
This is not an authoring format for me.
我继续用经典的风格。
I continue to use the idiom,
the classic style.
这就是模块格式的样子。
So here's what the module
format looks like.
您打开一个文件，然后开始创建变量和函数。
You open up a file and you just start
making variables and functions.
还有那个文件因为它会被装成一个模块
And that file,
because it's gonna be loaded as a module,
都假定一切都是私人的
is assumed that everything is private.
您不需要语法包装器。
You don't need a syntactic wrapper.
你可以在概念上把它裹在一个大的功能上。
You can conceptually of think of it
is being wrapped in a big function.
合并在缺省情况下为私有的作用域。
Wrapped in a scope that
is by default private.
你让某些东西成为公众的方式就是用这个出口关键词，
The way you make something public
is you use the export keyword,
就像你在第 3 行上看到的一样
like you see on line 3.
所以你出口的任何东西都是公开的
So anything you export is public,
您不导出的所有内容都是私有的。
everything that you
don't export is private.
其他要了解模块的情况是，它们是基于文件的。
The other thing to know about
modules is that they are file-based.
这意味着在同一文件中不可能有多个 ES6 模块。
Which means it is impossible to have more
than one ES6 module in the same file.
如果您的应用程序由 1000 个模块组成，
If your application is composed of say,
1,000 modules,
你的很多应用程序都是这样写在 ES6 模块中
the way many of your applications are,
and you write all of them in ES6 modules,
你会把它们都写为单独的文件就好了
you'll be writing them all as
separate files, which is fine.
但你不会有办法把这些 ES6
But there will not be a way for
you to take those ES6
当前表单中的模块，并将它们放入同一文件中。
modules in their current form and
ever put them into the same file.
这不是件事
That's not a thing.
例如，在没有构建过程的情况下，
So for example, without a build process,
如果你想把它装到一个浏览器里你就得载一千
if you wanted to ship them to a browser,
you're gonna have to load a thousand
具有所有性能影响的单独文件。
separate files with all
the performance implications thereof.
当前正在执行此操作的人员正在使用其作者所在的工具
People that are currently doing this
today are using tools where they author
在 ES6 模块中，并将其编译回旧的学校样式模块，并
in ES6 modules and they compile back
to the old school style module and
将它们并置为文件并将其关闭。
concatenate them into a file and
ship it off.
在我看来我只是在跳过中间人
And in my opinion,
I'm just skipping the middleman.
既然我们要重新编译旧的语法
Since we have to compile back
to that old syntax anyway,
我一直在写旧的语法
I just keep writing that old syntax.
但有些人发现这一格式的好处。
But some people are finding benefit
out of authoring this format.
因此，您可以创建一个模块，然后导出您想要的内容。
So you make a module and
you export what you want.
另外一件事要知道，不仅是基于文件，而且是单身。
The other thing to know, not only are they
file-based, but they're also singletons.
无论您将此模块导入到应用程序中多少次，
No matter how many times you import
this module into an application,
它只会运行一次
it only ever runs once.
而你每次进口的时候
And every other time that you import it,
你就会得到另一个这样的例子
you just get another reference
to that same instance.
因此，如果要为模块提供一个工厂，人们可以在其中制造多个模块
So if you want to have a factory for your
modules where people can make multiple
实例，您必须在 API上公开，这是用于执行该操作的工厂功能。
instances, you're gonna have to expose on
your API, a factory function to do that.